{"test_questions": [[{"question": "How many outputs are on a BCD decoder?", "opta": "4", "optb": "16", "optc": "8", "optd": "10", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a Gray code, each number is 3 greater than the binary representation of that number.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Use the weighting factors to convert the following BCD numbers to binary. 0101\u00a00011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a00010\u00a00110\u00a01000", "opta": "01010011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0001001101000", "optb": "11010100\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0100001100000", "optc": "110101\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0100001100", "optd": "101011\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0\u00a0001100001", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which digital system translates coded characters into a more useful form?", "opta": "encoder", "optb": "display", "optc": "counter", "optd": "decoder", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "From the following list of input conditions, determine the state of the five output leads on a 74148 octal-to-binary encoder.  I0 = 1 I3 = 1 I6 = 1 I1 = 1 I4 = 0 I7 = 1 I2 = 1 I5 = 1 EI = 0", "opta": "GS = L, A0 = L, A1 = L, A2 = H, EO = H", "optb": "GS = L, A0 = H, A1 = L, A2 = L, EO = H", "optc": "GS = L, A0 = L, A1 = H, A2 = L, EO = H", "optd": "GS = L, A0 = H, A1 = H, A2 = L, EO = H", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the function of an enable input on a multiplexer chip?", "opta": "to apply Vcc", "optb": "to connect ground", "optc": "to active the entire chip", "optd": "to active one half of the chip", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The expansion inputs to a comparator are used for expansion to a(n):", "opta": "4-bit system", "optb": "8-bit system", "optc": "BCD system", "optd": "counter system", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What do the mathematical symbols A < b and A > B mean?", "opta": "A < B means A is greater than B. A > B means A is less than B.", "optb": "A > B means A is less than B. A < B means A is greater than B.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A basic multiplexer principle can be demonstrated through the use of a:", "opta": "single-pole relay", "optb": "DPDT switch", "optc": "rotary switch", "optd": "linear stepper", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs will a decimal-to-BCD encoder have?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "10", "optd": "16", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A principle regarding most IC decoders is that when the correct input is present, the related output will switch:", "opta": "active-HIGH", "optb": "to a high impedance", "optc": "to an open", "optd": "active-LOW", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What control signals may be necessary to operate a 1-line-to-16 line decoder?", "opta": "flasher circuit control signal", "optb": "a LOW on all gate enable inputs", "optc": "input from a hexadecimal counter", "optd": "a HIGH on all gate enable circuits", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One multiplexer can take the place of:", "opta": "several SSI logic gates", "optb": "combinational logic circuits", "optc": "several Ex-NOR gates", "optd": "several SSI logic gates or combinational logic circuits", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many exclusive-NOR gates would be required for an 8-bit comparator circuit?", "opta": "4", "optb": "6", "optc": "8", "optd": "10", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs are required for a 1-of-10 BCD decoder?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "10", "optd": "1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A BCD decoder will have how many rows in its truth table?", "opta": "10", "optb": "9", "optc": "8", "optd": "3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many possible outputs would a decoder have with a 6-bit binary input?", "opta": "16", "optb": "32", "optc": "64", "optd": "128", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most demultiplexers facilitate which type of conversion?", "opta": "decimal-to-hexadecimal", "optb": "single input, multiple outputs", "optc": "ac to dc", "optd": "odd parity to even parity", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The inputs/outputs of an analog multiplexer/demultiplexer are:", "opta": "bidirectional", "optb": "unidirectional", "optc": "even parity", "optd": "binary-coded decimal", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why can a CMOS IC be used as both a multiplexer and a demultiplexer?", "opta": "It cannot be used as both.", "optb": "CMOS uses bidirectional switches.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One application of a digital multiplexer is to facilitate:", "opta": "data generation", "optb": "serial-to-parallel conversion", "optc": "parity checking", "optd": "data selector", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary use for Gray code is:", "opta": "coded representation of a shaft's mechanical position", "optb": "turning on/off software switches", "optc": "to represent the correct ASCII code to indicate the angular position of a shaft on rotating machinery", "optd": "to convert the angular position of a shaft on rotating machinery into hexadecimal code", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is a demultiplexer called a data distributor?", "opta": "The input will be distributed to one of the outputs.", "optb": "One of the inputs will be selected for the output.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the status of the inputs S0, S1, and S2 of the 74151 eight-line multiplexer in order for the output Y to be a copy of input I5?", "opta": "S0 = 0, S1 = 1, S2 = 0", "optb": "S0 = 0, S1 = 0, S2 = 1", "optc": "S0 = 1, S1 = 1, S2 = 0", "optd": "S0 = 1, S1 = 0, S2 = 1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One way to convert BCD to binary using the hardware approach is:", "opta": "with MSI IC circuits", "optb": "with a keyboard encoder", "optc": "with an ALU", "optd": "UART", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A microcontroller differs from a microprocessor in that it has several ________ ports and ________ built into its architecture, making it better suited for ________ applications.", "opta": "communication, PROMs, control", "optb": "parallel, logic gates, processing", "optc": "input/output, memory, control", "optd": "data, memory, decoding", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is an encoder different from a decoder?", "opta": "The output of an encoder is a binary code for 1-of-N input.", "optb": "The output of a decoder is a binary code for 1-of-N input.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is the Gray code more practical to use when coding the position of a rotating shaft?", "opta": "All digits change between counts.", "optb": "Two digits change between counts.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the following conditions on a 7485 magnitude comparator, what will be the state of each of the three outputs?   A0 = 0B0 = 1IA < B = 0 A1 = 1B1 = 0IA = B = 1 A2 = 1B2 = 0IA > B = 0 A3 = 0B3 = 0", "opta": "A = B = 0, A < B = 0, A > B = 1", "optb": "A = B = 0, A < B = 1, A > B = 0", "optc": "A = B = 1, A < B = 0, A > B = 0", "optd": "A = B = 0, A < B = 0, A > B = 0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When two or more inputs are active simultaneously, the process is called:", "opta": "first-in, first-out processing", "optb": "priority encoding", "optc": "ripple blanking", "optd": "first-in, first-out processing or priority encoding", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary code that progresses such that only one bit changes between two successive codes is:", "opta": "nine's-complement code", "optb": "8421 code", "optc": "excess-3 code", "optd": "Gray code", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a weighted value positional numbering system:", "opta": "hexadecimal", "optb": "binary-coded decimal", "optc": "binary", "optd": "octal", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs are required for a 1-of-16 decoder?", "opta": "2", "optb": "4", "optc": "8", "optd": "16", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A truth table with output columns numbered 0\u201315 may be for which type of decoder IC?", "opta": "hexadecimal 1-of-16", "optb": "dual octal outputs", "optc": "binary-to-hexadecimal", "optd": "hexadecimal-to-binary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a BCD-to-seven-segment converter, why must a code converter be utilized?", "opta": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into 7-bit code", "optb": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into 10-bit code", "optc": "to convert the 4-bit BCD into Gray code", "optd": "No conversion is necessary.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How can the active condition (HIGH or LOW) or the decoder output be determined from the logic symbol?", "opta": "A bubble indicates active-HIGH.", "optb": "A bubble indicates active-LOW.", "optc": "A square indicates active-HIGH.", "optd": "A square indicates active-LOW.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If two inputs are active on a priority encoder, which will be coded on the output?", "opta": "the higher value", "optb": "the lower value", "optc": "neither of the inputs", "optd": "both of the inputs", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A circuit that responds to a specific set of signals to produce a related digital signal output is called a(n):", "opta": "BCD matrix", "optb": "display driver", "optc": "encoder", "optd": "decoder", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many 74184 BCD-to-binary converters would be required to convert two complete BCD digits to a binary number?", "opta": "8", "optb": "4", "optc": "2", "optd": "1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many select lines would be required for an 8-line-to-1-line multiplexer?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "8", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}